<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Monster Journey</string>
    <string name="channel_name">Game Notifications</string>
    <string name="channel_description">Tells you when your monster has encounted an event.</string>
    <string name="icon_description">Current monster animation</string>
    <string name="arrow">View selection arrow</string>
    <string name="eggconfirm">Select Egg</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="confirm">Confirm</string>
    <string name="close">Close</string>
    <string name="volume">Volume: </string>
    <string name="pedometer">Run while app closed: </string>
    <string name="rate">Rate this game!</string>
    <string name="quit">Quit the app?</string>
    <string name="stepsneeded">Steps needed:\u0020</string>
    <string name="stepsevolve">Steps to evolve:\u0020</string>
    <string name="readytoevolve">Ready to evolve</string>
    <string name="maxstage">Monster is at Max Stage</string>
    <string name="partycollection">Current Monsters</string>

    <string name="removeads">Remove ads</string>
    <string name="buylightegg">Buy Light Egg</string>
    <string name="buydarkegg">Buy Dark Egg</string>
    <string name="buycosmicegg">Buy Cosmic Egg</string>
    <string name="buyitempack">Buy Item Pack</string>

    <string name="enemyfound">ENEMY FOUND</string>
    <string name="bossfound">BOSS FOUND</string>
    <string name="itemfound">ITEM FOUND</string>
    <string name="matchfound">MATCH FOUND</string>
    <string name="evolvefound">EVOLVE</string>

    <string name="playagain">Play Again</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="selector">Selected Task Display</string>

    <string name="monsterinfo">Monster Info</string>
    <string name="congratulations">Congratulations!</string>
    <string name="entername">Please enter a name for your new Monster: </string>

<!--    Map Completed-->
    <string name="newegg">New egg unlocked!</string>
    <string name="evolutiondiscount">Cost for evolution reduced.</string>
    <string name="evolutionitem">Earned an evolution drug.</string>

    <string name="Training">Training</string>
    <string name="Traininginfo">Train your monster!</string>
    <string name="TrainingReady">Ready?</string>
    <string name="TrainingStart">Tap to gather energy!</string>
    <string name="TrainingSuccess">Training Success!</string>
    <string name="TrainingFailed">Training Failed…</string>

    <string name="Feeding">Feeding</string>
    <string name="Feedinginfo">Feed your monster!</string>

    <string name="FoodTitle1">Small Apple</string>
    <string name="FoodDescription1">A basic food item. Restores half a heart upon consumption</string>

    <string name="FoodTitle2">Large Apple</string>
    <string name="FoodDescription2">A food item. Restores a heart upon consumption</string>

    <string name="FoodTitle3">Meat</string>
    <string name="FoodDescription3">A large food item. Restores one and a half a heart upon consumption</string>

    <string name="FoodTitle4">Training Pill</string>
    <string name="FoodDescription4">Restores one diligence heart upon consumption.</string>

    <string name="FoodTitle5">Evolution Drug</string>
    <string name="FoodDescription5">A rare item. Reduces steps needed to evolve by 1000.</string>

    <string name="Evolve">Evolve</string>
    <string name="EvolveInfo">Evolve your monster if conditions have been met.</string>

    <string name="Retire">Retire</string>
    <string name="Retireinfo">Send your monster off to retirement and start raising a new one.</string>
    <string name="RetireConfirm">Are you sure you want to retire your current monster? You will start off with a new egg if you confirm.</string>
    <string name="ReleaseConfirm">Are you sure you want to release this monster? You won\'t be able to get it back if you confirm.</string>

    <string name="Matchmaking">Matchmaking</string>
    <string name="Matchmakinginfo">Search for a match for your monster!</string>

    <string name="BattleFriend">Battle</string>
    <string name="BattleFriendInfo">Connect and battle with another nearby person\'s monster.</string>

    <string name="BreedFriend">Match</string>
    <string name="BreedingFriendInfo">Connect with another person\'s monster and create a new egg. (Caution: will retire your current monster if ranch is full, both players must have an adult stage monster.)</string>
    <string name="BreedingFriendMessage">Mufufu, looks like you met a friend. Shall we make this a match? (This will retire your current monster if your ranch is full)</string>

    <string name="RockFriend">Rock Paper Scissors</string>
    <string name="RockDescription">Challenge a nearby player to rock paper scissors. The first one to get 3 points wins!</string>

    <string name="Player1">Player 1: </string>
    <string name="Player2">Player 2: </string>
    <string name="win_message">Round won!</string>
    <string name="tie_message">Tie!</string>
    <string name="loss_message">Round lost!</string>

    <string name="game_win">Game Won!</string>
    <string name="game_lost">Game Lost!</string>

    <string name="MatchmakerEarly">Hello young soul. I am the matchmaker. Once your monster has grown seek me again so I may find it a suitor.</string>
    <string name="MatchmakerText">Hello old soul. I am the matchmaker. Bear your heart to me and I shall find you a suitor. Shall I look for a match for your monster?</string>
    <string name="MatchmakerFound">I come bearing a match. Do you accept this proposition? (This will retire your current monster if your ranch is full)</string>

    <string name="BattleTitle">Battle!</string>
    <string name="BattleEnemyHealth">Enemy Health: </string>
    <string name="BattlePlayerHealth">Player Health: </string>

    <string name="simonsays">Memory game button</string>
    <string name="hungerbar">Hunger Bar</string>
    <string name="trainingbar">Training Bar</string>

    <string name="diligence">DILIGENCE: </string>
    <string name="hunger">HUNGER: </string>

    <string name="simonsays_title">Memory Repetition</string>
    <string name="simonsays_description">A memory game where you must select buttons in the same pattern presented. Earn steps for each round you pass.</string>

    <string name="snake_title">Chain connect</string>
    <string name="snake_description">Move a chain along to collect blocks and become longer. Earn steps for each block you collect.</string>

    <string name="rock">Rock</string>
    <string name="paper">Paper</string>
    <string name="scissors">Scissors</string>

    <string name="searching">Searching…</string>
    <string name="searchmessage">Please wait at least 10 seconds for search to finish.</string>

    <string name="mapcompleted">Completed</string>
    <string name="mapnotcompleted">Not Completed</string>

    <string name="firetype">Fire</string>
    <string name="dinotype">Dino</string>
    <string name="aquatype">Aqua</string>
    <string name="enigmatype">Enigma</string>
    <string name="earthtype">Earth</string>
    <string name="machinetype">Machine</string>
    <string name="darktype">Dark</string>
    <string name="lighttype">Light</string>
    <string name="cosmictype">Cosmic</string>

    <string name="firedescription">A scorching island in a sea of flames. Monsters that live here have learned to adapt to the extreme heat.</string>
    <string name="dinodescription">An ancient island full of savage terrain. Dino type monsters can be found here.</string>
    <string name="aquadescription">An island of coral and sea life. Monsters here are accustomed to living in the sea.</string>
    <string name="enigmadescription">A strange land inhabited by Enigma type monsters. Spirits and strange beings can be found here.</string>
    <string name="earthdescription">An island that has been overrun with foliage. Monsters here have become one with nature.</string>
    <string name="machinedescription">An island built out of metal. The lack of organic materials has caused it to be full of machines.</string>
    <string name="darkdescription">An island covered in dark miasma. Monsters on this island have become one with darkness</string>
    <string name="lightdescription">An island in the clouds surrounded by light. Monsters here are accustomed to the constant daytime.</string>
    <string name="cosmicdescription">An island that is said to have once been in the stars. All the monsters here are celestial beings.</string>

    <string name="missing_title">Not Found</string>
    <string name="missing_description">This entry hasn\'t been unlocked yet.</string>

    <string name="egg_list">Eggs Collected: </string>
    <string name="basic_egg_title">Enigma Egg</string>
    <string name="basic_egg_description">A seemingly basic egg. Contains an enigma type monster.</string>
    <string name="dino_egg_title">Dino Egg</string>
    <string name="dino_egg_description">A prehistoric egg. Contains an ancient type monster.</string>
    <string name="aqua_egg_title">Aqua Egg</string>
    <string name="aqua_egg_description">An aquatic egg. Contains an aquatic type monster.</string>
    <string name="fire_egg_title">Fire Egg</string>
    <string name="fire_egg_description">A fiery egg. Contains a fire type monster.</string>
    <string name="machine_egg_title">Machine Egg</string>
    <string name="machine_egg_description">An egg made out of metal. Contains a machine type monster.</string>
    <string name="earth_egg_title">Earth Egg</string>
    <string name="earth_egg_description">An egg that sprouted from the earth. Contains an earth type monster.</string>

    <string name="baby_list">Babies Collected: </string>

<!--    Enigma descriptions-->
    <string name="enigma_baby_tanuki_title">Mangut</string>
    <string name="enigma_baby_tanuki_description">An enigma type monster. Although it is actually a spirit, this monster strangely resembles a raccoon.
        It will spend most of its time hiding and playing in forests.</string>

    <string name="enigma_baby_skull_title">Rattle</string>
    <string name="enigma_baby_skull_description">An enigma type monster. Some believe it eerily resembles a skull but Researchers have found
    that they appear to be made of a more brittle material, which is why they often hide from strangers.</string>

    <string name="enigma_child_tanuki_title">JudaiMangut</string>
    <string name="enigma_child_tanuki_description">An enigma type monster. Folklore mentions this monster as a symbol of wealth and prosperity. Because of
    this they have been hunted to the point where finding one in the wild is a rarity.</string>

    <string name="enigma_child_mushroom_title">Sporesitter</string>
    <string name="enigma_child_mushroom_description">An enigma type monster. Commonly found in forests this monster is very social with those it deems friends.</string>

    <string name="enigma_child_snake_title">Scaley</string>
    <string name="enigma_child_snake_description">An enigma type monster. A symbol of the desert. This monster spends a lot of time alone so it becomes
    startled and unpredictable when something new approaches.</string>

    <string name="enigma_adult_sphinx_title">Riddler</string>
    <string name="enigma_adult_sphinx_description">This enigma type monster strangely resembles a sphinx. It spends most of its time lounging around in front of
    caves and passageways. Only allowing passage to whoever can solve its riddles.</string>
    <string name="basic_baby1_title">Eye</string>
    <string name="basic_baby1_description">An enigma type monster. It can\'t move its main body so it waits and gazes at the passing world.</string>

<!--    <string name="basic_baby2_title">Sparky</string>-->
<!--    <string name="basic_baby2_description">A fire type monster. Enjoys sitting around campfires and eating stray embers.</string>-->

    <!--    Dino descriptions-->
    <string name="dino_baby1_title">Chomper</string>
    <string name="dino_baby1_description">A dino type monster. Once it bites onto something it never lets go so watch out!</string>

    <string name="dino_baby_dinoegg_title">Hider</string>
    <string name="dino_baby_dinoegg_description">A dino type monster. As a cold and shy baby it hides inside its egg shell so it can remain warm and comfortable.</string>

    <string name="dino_baby2_title">Dozer</string>
    <string name="dino_baby2_description">A dino type monster. It sleeps for 20 hours a day and only wakes up to eat or when bothered.</string>

    <string name="dino_adult_ankylosaur_title">Ankylo</string>
    <string name="dino_adult_ankylosaur_description">Covered in scales, this dino type monster protects itself while bludgeoning enemies with its tail</string>

    <string name="child_list">Children Collected: </string>
    <string name="dino_child2_title">Ripper</string>
    <string name="dino_child2_description">A dino type monster. A dangerous savage who will attack anything that enters its territory.</string>

    <string name="adult_list">Adults Collected: </string>

    <!--    Earth descriptions-->
    <string name="baby_earth_seed_title">Seedo</string>
    <string name="baby_earth_seed_description">An earth type monster. This seemingly simple seed will one day grow up to be a large monster… or at
    least that\'s what it tells its friends.</string>

    <string name="baby_earth_peas_title">Peas</string>
    <string name="baby_earth_peas_description">An earth type monster. For a long time researchers have wondered if this monster is actually three monsters
    gathered together or a monster with three heads.</string>

    <!--    Aqua descriptions-->
    <string name="baby_aqua_tadpole_title">Taddy</string>
    <string name="baby_aqua_tadpole_description">An aqua type monster. Born in a small lake it slowly crawls outside to meet new friends.</string>

    <string name="baby_aqua_octopus_title">Octo</string>
    <string name="baby_aqua_octopus_description">An aqua type monster. With its many arms it floats around hoping small prey will get stuck in its tentacles.</string>

    <string name="child_aqua_eel_title">Eely</string>
    <string name="child_aqua_eel_description">This aqua type monster is often mistaken by some cultures as a mythical dragon. It is however actually a type of eel.</string>

    <string name="child_aqua_pufferfish_title">Paulo</string>
    <string name="child_aqua_pufferfish_description">When threatened this aqua type monster will expand to try and intimidate the threat. It also expands when happy,
       which is… confusing.</string>

    <string name="child_aqua_watertoad_title">Aqua Toad</string>
    <string name="child_aqua_watertoad_description">This aqua type monster stores water in a sac on its back. The water combines with mucus on its skin to produce large bubbles.</string>

    <string name="child_aqua_bubblething_title">Bubbles</string>
    <string name="child_aqua_bubblething_description">This aqua type monster hides in a large bubble made of water. It will keep adding water to its bubble and try and
        replace any water lost on hot days.</string>

    <string name="child_aqua_clam_title">Clamman</string>
    <string name="child_aqua_clam_description">Normally found at the bottom of the ocean, this aqua type monster will come up for air every few days to socialize.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_jellyfish_title">Jellish</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_jellyfish_description">This aqua type monster has no bones. Because of this it floats around hoping smaller creatures get caught in its tentacles.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_walrus_title">Walno</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_walrus_description">This aqua type monster spends most of its time relaxing on beaches with its herd. The largest one is in charge of keeping a lookout
    for threats while the others sleep.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_whaleseal_title">Whalepup</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_whaleseal_description">Found on beaches it will use its cute appearance to befriend other monsters and join their group.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_waterdragon_title">Haku</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_waterdragon_description">According to legend, a carp that could swim upstream and then leap the falls of the Yellow River at Dragon Gate
        would be transformed into a dragon. Researchers have tossed carp through this gate but it appears that unless a carp makes the journey itself it will not transform.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_footballfish_title">Angler</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_footballfish_description">Because of its fearsome appearance this monster likes to hide in the dark depths of the sea. It will use the light as a lure to
    draw prey closer before it strikes.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_octopus_title">Octolock</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_octopus_description">This strange monster has no bones. Because of this it is able to hide and squeeze through tight crevasses on the ocean floor.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_stingray_title">Stinghy</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_stingray_description">This monster uses sensors on its body to detect electric signals from passing organisms to hunt its prey.</string>

    <string name="adult_aqua_scaleyfootsnail_title">Pangolo</string>
    <string name="adult_aqua_scaleyfootsnail_description">The shell on this monster is actually made out of iron, which it will collect on the sea floor over its life. All of its
    feet are covered in tiny iron scales as well for further protection.</string>

    <!--   Machine descriptions-->
    <string name="adult_machine_driller_title">Mach Gurren</string>
    <string name="adult_machine_driller_description">A machine type monster. Originally a simple drilling machine used for construction that has been taken over
    by an unknown cybernetic organism. Its dream is to drill to the heavens.</string>

    <!--   Fire descriptions-->
    <string name="baby_fire_sparky_title">Sparky</string>
    <string name="baby_fire_sparky_description">A fire type monster. Enjoys sitting around campfires and eating stray embers.</string>

    <string name="baby_fire_fat_title">Bailu</string>
    <string name="baby_fire_fat_description">A fire type monster. Some cultures carry totems based on it for good luck and fortune.</string>

    <string name="child_fire_chameleon_title">Chameon</string>
    <string name="child_fire_chameleon_description">This horned monster carries a small fire on its back. This fire is used to regulate its internal temperature.</string>

    <string name="child_fire_toad_title">Fire Toad</string>
    <string name="child_fire_toad_description">This fire type monster stores fuel in a sac on its back. The fuel produces strong flames which are expelled constantly.</string>

    <string name="child_fire_seaturtle_title">Turtu</string>
    <string name="child_fire_seaturtle_description">The shell on its back is actually a miniature volcano. This monster mainly eats stones which are melted in its core to
    filter out nutrients it can digest.</string>

    <string name="child_fire_fireball_title">Sputter</string>
    <string name="child_fire_fireball_description">This ball of fire has obtained sentience through some bizarre accident. Through fear of eventually burning out it
    will search out smaller flames to consume.</string>

    <string name="child_fire_wyvern_title">Baogon</string>
    <string name="child_fire_wyvern_description">A rare wyrm thought to be a descendant of ancient dragons. Despite having wings it spends most of its time slithering
    on the ground.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_fireball_title">Bo-bo-bo-bo</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_fireball_description">Once a smaller fireball it has managed to consume enough flames that it has become large and complacent.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_factorygorilla_title">Factorilla</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_factorygorilla_description">A mad scientist has combined this monster with a factory. Because of this it now has a large chimney
    on its back that expels flames from its internal furnace.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_snake_title">Serpentia</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_snake_description">In the harsh heat of its environment this monster has been forced to develop fierce instincts to survive.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_tikimask_title">MakuMaku</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_tikimask_description">Indigenous tribes on small islands worship this monster believing it will protect them on fishing trips.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_serpent_title">Pyrosnake</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_serpent_description">In the extreme heat of the desert this monster can be found. The heat also produces mirages which makes studying it difficult.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_firelordgoat_title">Baahlzebub</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_firelordgoat_description">Despite its fearsome appearance this monster is quite kind. It will spend most of its time caring for baby
    monsters. It also guards them so be careful not to get too close.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_fox_title">Fennefire</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_fox_description">This monster uses its large ears to detect anything hiding in its surroundings. Flames from its tail let others know
    not to get too close.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_elemental_title">Smoldris</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_elemental_description">A living being made of coal. The friction from moving causes the coal to ignite which creates the large mane of fire
    surrounging it.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_spirit_title">Agnis</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_spirit_description">A spirit that is said to be the embodiment of fire. It contains its energy within the large beads around its neck
    which can be used to generate all sorts of flames.</string>

    <string name="adult_fire_baby_title">HouSu</string>
    <string name="adult_fire_baby_description">With many coals on its back this monster constantly generates heat. It is very popular in hot springs.</string>

    <!--   Dark descriptions-->
    <string name="dark_egg_title">Dark</string>
    <string name="dark_egg_description">An egg shrouded in darkness. Contains a dark type monster.</string>

    <!--   Light descriptions-->
    <string name="light_egg_title">Light</string>
    <string name="light_egg_description">An egg that has descended from the heavens. Contains a light type monster.</string>

    <!--   Cosmic descriptions-->
    <string name="cosmic_egg_title">Cosmic</string>
    <string name="cosmic_egg_description">An egg that was found among the stars. Contains a cosmic type monster.</string>

    <string name="cosmic_baby1_title">Stardu</string>
    <string name="cosmic_baby1_description">A monster made up of bright stardust. Enjoys spending time with others.</string>

    <string name="cosmic_baby2_title">Stardi</string>
    <string name="cosmic_baby2_description">A monster made up of dark stardust. Likes to be alone.</string>

</resources>